<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | FAIAS</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/icon_hu85bf0bbc0816d1dd04ec94c6db8981cf_47271_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Result 1: Guideline for teachers in formal education</title>
      <link>/project/result1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/result1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This intellectual output, devoted to secondary teachers, will be an easy-and-ready to-use handbook that will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce teachers (especially those who are without experience and/or are skeptical on the use of AI in humanistic topics) into the AI word.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Showcase appealing and inspiring examples and resources of how to use A.I. in the classroom covering different topics, and ranging from science to math, from literature to philosophy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Result 2: Inclusion Guide for non-formal educators</title>
      <link>/project/result2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/result2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This intellectual output, devoted to non-formal educators and STEAM activity organizers, will be a handbook that will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce our target group to Artificial Intelligence while explaining why diversity is so important in this field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tackle actively the diversity perspective from the point of view of gender.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce the topic of bias in AI algorithms and Showcase practical examples of this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Showcase ‘inclusive’ AI resources that can be used in STEAM activities, and non-formal education activities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommend how to organize gender balance STEAM activities on AI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Result 3: Interactive Learning Tool</title>
      <link>/project/result3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/result3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LearningML aims to be a free/open-source web-based platform aimed to bring Machine Learning (ML) fundamentals in a practical way to children or people interested in the growing field of AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tool provides a platform intended to build ML models from example data, and a Programming Platform allowing to code creative applications using those models. At this point, LearningML is a proof of concept to explore whether machine learning algorithms can be executed locally in the browser in order to avoid the use of an AI cloud service when designing a tool to learn ML. We aim to further develop LearningML so that it becomes a comprehensive free/open-source tool for learning AI at schools in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;boton&#34; href=&#34;https://web.learningml.org/en/home-spanish-en-translation/&#34; &gt; &lt;strong&gt;Go to Project Site&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
